Yung-Te Chen (Peter)

E-mail: peterchencc@gmail.com

Links: linkedin.com/in/peterchencc | github.com/peterchencc | www.peterchen.cc

SUMMARY

6+ years experience in software development, focusing on web platform. Passionate about delivering the best product experience. Experienced working with global team and help bridge the tech feasibility and business needs. Participated in tech conferences and meet-ups, and help others to learn new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer — Burpple

Singapore Feb 2018 – Dec 2019

Burpple is a leading food reviews platform in Singapore that helps people find the perfect places to eat.

- Took full ownership on web platform by using Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js. Worked closely with design and product team to launch new features, iterated on core functions to deliver best user experiences.
- Part of the engineering team that built Burpple Beyond, an 1-for-1 deals subscription program. Integrated Stripe payment and OTP verification on web, and focused on front-end tasks such as activation flow, referral program.
- Integrated Vue.js to built several single-page apps for cross-device features such as authentication, dining feedback and suggest edits for venue's info. Implemented AMP (Accelerated Mobile Pages) on web pages.
- Increased 30% of performance score on key pages by optimizing page loading and structure.
- Collaborated with product and marketing teams for marketing campaigns on web and push notification by integrate CleverTap. And implement Amplitude for product analytics data tracking.

Full Stack Web Developer — Meet.jobs

Taipei City, Taiwan Oct 2015 — Aug 2017

Meet.jobs is a job and recruiting platform for global.

- As the first engineer in this startup, built the job site from scratch, took on product management responsibility, iterated on the product to optimize experience for users and also accommodate revenue model evolvement.
- Developed all key features for internationalization site by Ruby on Rails, MySQL, JavaScript.
- Set up CI/CD pipeline and agile development flow, hosted servers on Linode with Ubuntu, Nginx, Monit, Backup.
- Developed job application system includes group messages, email notification (Amazon SES), referral system.
- Built employer-side dashboard includes multi-user authorization and Stripe to process payment.
- Maintained admin panel includes overview of tracking data, integrated customized notification to Slack.
- Built job searching function (with ElasticSearch), job crawler and CMS for blog.

Web Development Intern — Tinkerbox Studios

Singapore Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

• Part of an agile team to built a home tutor platform using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL.

Web Programmer — Appscomb.net Media, Cite Media Holding Group

Taipei City, Taiwan Sep 2012 – Jun 2014

Appscomb.net is a digital media that focus tech news, product reviews, interior design and traveling.

- Top 3 for the company's performance evaluations for two seasons in a row.
- Maintained 4 websites and over 20 mobile apps API based on PHP Ctemplate framework, MySQL with FreeBSD.
- Developed push notification API and cron job that catches blogs RSS feeds and Facebook timeline data.
- Developed event ticket and promotion coupon that can be downloaded on Apple Wallet.

COURSES

Full-stack Advanced React & GraphQL, wesbos.com

Jun 2020

• An online course to build full stack JavaScript apps with Next.js + Apollo and GraphQL + Node.js

React For Beginners, wesbos.com

Feb 2020

• An online course to learn React.js + Firebase apps and website components

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp, Alpha Camp

Mar 2015 - May 2015

- 10 week full-time training of lectures, workshops, projects and 1:1 coding review. Built applications like forums, social networking platforms and E-commerce sites by Ruby on Rails.
- Final project: web platform that let users find sports coach based on Rails and MySQL with API for iOS client.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration, Soochow University, Taipei City, Taiwan

Majored in Computer Science and Information Management

Sep 2007 – Jun 2011

• Graduation final project - Worked as part of a team of 3 students to develop a simple ticket selling platform using PHP, which allowed tickets to be downloaded with a scanned encrypt QRCode.

OTHERS

Teaching Assistant, ALPHA Camp

2017

- As a teaching assistant for full-time web development bootcamp in Singapore, held daily office hours to provide support to students' learning process.
- Reviewed curriculum and developed teaching material for online web development course.

Freelance Project, LifeBerry Shop E-commerce website

2017

• Developed an E-commerce website with admin panel using Ruby on Rails, integrated Pay2Go payment service.